Diya Zhao- Front End Web Developer

dzhao0225@gmail.com, Phone Number: 305-877-0087, San Francisco, CA

Summary

Front-end developer skilled in writing, clean, testable UI code. Experienced with React, jQuery, Node, JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Also has experience with modern tooling and is excited to learn and pick up the right tools for the job.

Skills

Advanced: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, APIs.

Proficient: MongoDB, Responsive mobile-first design, TDD with Mocha, Webpack.

Recent Projects

<u>Lessbuy:</u> A complete shopping App with functions to login in, register, add items into shopping cart and checkout. Built with Node, Express and Mongo.

<u>Trailor Engine</u>: A full stack online movie-trailer finder. Built with React, Node, Express and Mongo and Youtube API.

<u>Catch Javascript Meetup</u>: A search App using Javascript to search local "meet-ups" using zip code. Built with HTML, CSS, jQuery, Ajax. Used Google Map's APIs and Meetup APIs.

Experience

Dealmoon Union City, CA

Travel Editor 06/2015 - 05/2016

- Managed, edited and created content for the Tourism and Travel section of Dealmoon's website.
- Higher quality and more in-depth articles resulted in a 10% increase in DAU in 6 months.
- Coordinated with Director of Marketing and Sales to conduct creative meetings to develop and strategize different project concepts.

Bigfoot Entertainment Miami, FL

Presenter and Producer of Fashion Frontline 02/2013 – 08/2013

- Worked part-time during school as a Presenter and Producer for a show focused on global fashion trends.
- Responsible for presenting fashion, entertainment, and lifestyle news from all over the world.
- Worked with production team with planning new broadcasting patterns and reported new topics to attract different demographic viewers.

Education

THINKFUL

Web Development Intensive 06/2016-01/2017

- Completed a comprehensive, six-month course on modern full stack JavaScript development.
- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating weekly with a senior web developer.

Florida International University

Master's Degree, Hospitality Management 2012-2014

Tianjin University of Commerce

Double Major, Tourism Management & Hospitality Management 2008-2012